Guide to the Mick Moloney Collection of Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Videotapes AIA.031.005
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Videotapes
1982-2000
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Moloney, Mick, 1944-
AIA.031.005
7 Linear Feet in 7 record cartons.
These videotapes are part of the larger Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Collection. This sub-collection consists of VHS cassettes, Beta videocassette tapes, and U-Matic videocassettes acquired in the course of Dr. Moloney's career as a folklorist, producer, musician, and academic. The tapes include amateur and professional recordings of Dr. Moloney's performances, extensive documentation of the 1987 International Village Fair, commercial videotapes collected as teaching aids, and videotapes used as masters and safeties for recording sessions.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
The Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Collection is composed of five parts. Taken together, they illustrate Dr. Moloney's career long engagement with Irish-American culture across a wide variety of media with a particular focus on Irish and Irish-American music.
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Commercial Recordings (AIA 031.1)
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Field Recordings (AIA 031.2)
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Papers (AIA 031.3)
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Irish Americana (AIA 031.4)
Dorothy Hayden Cudahy Irish Memories Collection (AIA 001) Susan McKeown Papers (AIA 032)
Arrangement
The videotapes are arranged in one series, Series I: Videotapes, 1982-2000. The series is arranged alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
Dr. Mick Moloney (1944-) is a musician, folklorist, and Global Distinguished Professor of Music and Irish Studies at New York University. He immigrated to the United States in 1973, earning a Ph.D. in folklore and folklife from the University of Pennsylvania. He has recorded and produced over forty albums of traditional music, acted as advisor for scores of festivals and concerts, and served as artistic director for the musical ensemble The Green Fields of America. In 1999, Moloney was awarded the National Heritage Award of the National Endowment of the Arts, the highest official honor of traditional artist can receive in the United States.
Moloney is the author of Far from the Shamrock Shore (2002) and numerous essays on Irish music and musical culture, and the co-editor of Close to the Floor: Irish Dance from the Boreen to Broadway (2009).
Sources: Steve Winnick, "From Limerick Rake to Solid Man: The Musical Life of Mick Moloney," Dirty Linen, No. 48 (October/November 1993) 1999 NEA National Heritage Fellowships: http://www.nea.gov/honors/heritage/fellows/fellow.php?id=1999_11 Mick Moloney, Musician and Folklorist: http://www.mickmoloney.com
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Custodial History Note
New York University's Division of Libraries, in conjunction with Glucksman Ireland House at New York University, purchased the Mick Moloney Collection of Irish-American Music and Popular Culture for the Archives of Irish America in 2006. Until transfer to Bobst Library under the supervision of its Head of Collections, Dr. Michael Nash, the materials in this collection were stored in Dr. Moloney's house in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 2006.071 and 2010.019.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
The tapes are in three formats: VHS cassette, Beta cassette and U-Matic cassette.
Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that already have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy be made, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Content Note
These videotapes are part of the larger Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Collection. This sub-collection consists of VHS cassettes, Beta videocassette tapes, and U-Matic videocassettes acquired in the course of Dr. Moloney's career as a folklorist, producer, musician, and academic. The tapes include amateur and professional recordings of Dr. Moloney's performances, extensive documentation of the 1987 International Village Fair, commercial videotapes collected as teaching aids, and videotapes used as masters and safeties for recording sessions. The materials illustrate themes such as immigration and assimilation viewed through the lens of Irish-America's engagement with and expression of its own popular culture, with specific emphasis on its musical traditions. The time period most heavily documented in this subcollection (1975-2000) witnessed both a reinvestment by Irish-America in its cultural traditions and a transition of its musical traditions from the home to the stage, accompanied by unprecedented national recognition. The subcollection illustrates the shifts in policies regarding arts funding and programming; the valorization of ethnicity in the United States during the late 20th century; the rise in prominence of female performers of traditional music; and the Irish presence on and repertoire of the Philadelphia and New York music scenes.
The majority of the videotapes document Moloney's live performances, including those at Irish and folk festivals held in Dallas, Philadelphia, Washington, D.C. (Glen Echo), and the Augusta Heritage Center's Irish Week at Elkins College, West Virginia. Dr. Moloney's involvement in the International Village Fair; his touring ensemble, the Green Fields of America; and his collaboration with Robbie O'Connell and Jimmy Keane, are particularly well represented. Some tapes contains audio masters and safety copies of recording sessions for Dr. Moloney and the traditional ensemble Cherish the Ladies. Other items of note include broadcasts, tapes related to Moloney's package tours of Ireland, and a recording of the ceremony at which Moloney received the National Heritage Fellowship Award in 1999.
Irish Americans -- Music.; Recording session.; San Francisco (Calif.); Session (seisun).; Washington (D.C.); Workshops (seminars); Competitions.; Compilation.; Concerts.; Demonstrations (presentation events).; Ceili.; Interviews.; Broadcasts.; Irish Americans -- Social life and customs.; Irish -- Songs and music.; Irish -- Music; Music festivals.; Music |x Competitions.; Irish Americans.; New York (N.Y.).; Oral history.; Philadelphia (Pa.); Music schools.; Private performance.; Britton, Tim; Egan, Seamus, 1969-; McGreevy, Johnny, 1919-; O'Donnell, Eugene, 1932-; McComiskey, Billy; Ochs, Bill; Ivers, Eileen; McGlynn, Sean; Keane, Jimmy; Rafferty, Mike, 1926-; Carroll, Liz, 1957-; Neary, Eleanor Kane, 1915-1993; Keane, James, 1948-; Coen, Jack; O'Connell, Robbie; Coen, Charlie, Fr., 1934-; Cahill, Eddie
- Series I: Videotapes, 1982-2000, 7 Linear Feet (7 boxes)
  - 15th Annual Irish Concert at Gaston Hall, Georgetown Univsity, Tape 2 of 2, Video: Abby Sternberg, Feb 24, 1995 (Box 3, Video 76)
  - "15th Annual Mick Moloney Irish Concert," Gaston Hall, Georgetown University, 02/24/95, Tape 1 of 2, Video: Abby Sternberg, RT 85: 51, Feb 24, 1995 (Box 1, Video 2)
  - 1999 National Heritage Fellowship Concert and Awards Ceremony (Box 2, Video 27)
  - All Ireland Senior Competitions, Accordion and Ceili Bands, undated (Box 2, Video 55)
  - "Julie Andrews' Invitation to the Dance," Green Grass Cloggers, CBS Festival of Lively Arts for Children, undated (Box 3, Video 85)
  - Annual Concert-St. Malachy, undated (Box 4, Video 106)
  - As Played by Joe Derrane, Produced by Frank Ferrel, RT: 26:55, 1994 (Box 3, Video 74)
  - Augusta '88, Week 3, 1988 (Box 1, Video 35)
  - BBC Documentary, I Want my Boy Back: One Family's Journey Through the Son-Rise Program, RT 55:00, undated (Box 1, Video 3)
  - Beginning Old Time Banjo with Evo Bluestein: A Lark in the Morning, Instructional Video, 1987 (Box 3, Video 67)
  - Black Arts for M.M., undated (Box 1, Video 15)
  - Boatbuilding (U-Matic 20 min.), undated (Box 5, Video 123)
  - John Bradshaw, Eight Stages of Man, undated (Box 1, Video 5)
  - Celebration Northeast: Hanover, New Hampshire, Mick Moloney, Lil Carroll, D. Golden, Green Grass Cloggers, Jethro Burrs, Leny and Donna Lamb, La Vaughn Robinson, Jul, 1983 (Box 3, Video 84)
  - Celtic Appalachia, undated (Box 2, Video 37)
  - Celtic Celebration, Producer: Gallagher, Editor: Finkbiner, Jan 27, 1993 (Box 3, Video 65)
  - Cherish the Ladies, Les Montagnards, Cape Breton Trio, undated (Box 4, Video 120)
  - Cherish the Ladies, Master Beta 1 (Beta), Oct, 1985 (Box 4, Video 114)
  - Christmas Party; Vaudeville Concert, I. House-Part II, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Video 62)
  - "Community College Today," Irish Cultural Prog., Moloney/O'Donnell, Mar 2, 1982 (Box 3, Video 86)
  - Copy-Ftg. M. Moloney, #2, Jun 21, 1988 (Box 2, Video 30)
  - Dallas Irish Festival, Mar 1993 (Box 3, Video 78)
  - Dance Party, Kapelye, Sandy Chovkroun, Terrence Cameron and Steel Kings (U-Matic 60 min.), undated (Box 7, Video 157)
  - Did Your Mother Come From Ireland? (U-Matic 60 min.), undated (Box 6, Video 150)
  - Ethnic Notions, undated (Box 1, Video 10)
  - Evening in the Glen; Irish Echoes in the Glen, undated (Box 2, Video 46)
  - Evolution, undated (Box 1, Video 12)
  - Far Away from the Shamrock Shore, A History of Irish Music in America, 1994 (Box 2, Video 29)
  - Fathers and Daughters #1-21 (Beta U-Matic 20 min.), Oct, 1985 (Box 4, Video 110)
  - Fathers and Daughters #22-38 (Beta), undated (Box 4, Video 115)
  - Fathers and Daughters Beta II and Beta I, (Beta), Oct, 1985 (Box 4, Video 118)
  - Fathers and Daughters/ Pro.-Mick Moloney, Safety (Beta U-Matic 20 min.), undated (Box 4, Video 113)
  - Folklore Tour Ireland, undated (Box 2, Video 48)
  - "Fresh Paint," Nigel Noble, Pam Nelson/Kim Ricotta, Pat McKorkel, Oct 6, 1995 (Box 3, Video 77)
  - Georgetown University-Gaston Hall Irish Concert, Tape 1 of 2, Audio Feed Middle Orchestra Camera, Camera: Abby Sternberg, Feb 24, 1995 (Box 3, Video 88)
  - Glen Echo Irish Folk Festival, undated (Box 2, Video 40)
  - Savion Glover at the White House, undated (Box 1, Video 9)
  - Liz Grave's Speech to Tour, Belfast and Tory Island and Derry-Michael Dunlavey, Jun, 1998 (Box 4, Video 93)
  - Green Fields of America, Glen Echo Irish Fest, 1984 (Box 3, Video 73)
  - Green Fields of America, Glen Echo Irish Festival, 5/29/1989, May 29, 1989 (Box 1, Video 14)
  - Green Fields of America presented by Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann Irish Musicians Association, Apr 22, 1995 (Box 4, Video 103)
  - Green Fields of America-some with Goldens and Hunts (U-Matic 20 min.), undated (Box 5, Video 122)
  - Green Fields of America, Town Hall, Tape 1 (of 2), Dec 4, 1998 (Box 4, Video 108)
  - Mrs. Sue Henhoeffer's 80th Birthday Party, undated (Box 2, Video 43)
  - Horses Sing None of It-Mick Moloney and Friends, May 31, 1994 (Box 3, Video 68)
  - Horses Sing None of It, Ralph Litwin, Producer and Host, Mick Moloney and Friends, Part 2 (U-Matic 60 min.), May 31, 1994 (Box 7, Video 151)
  - Horses Sing None of It, Ralph Litwin, Producer and Host, Mick Moloney and Friends, Part 1 (U-Matic 60 min.), May 31, 1994 (Box 7, Video 152)
  - International Festival, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - International House-Vaudeville, undated (Box 1, Video 33)
  - IVF (U-Matic 20 min.), 1987 (Box 5, Video 138)
  - IVF (U-Matic 20 min.), 1987 (Box 5, Video 134)
  - IVF (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 26, 1987 (Box 6, Video 148)
  - IVF (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 26, 1987 (Box 6, Video 147)
  - IVF (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 26, 1987 (Box 5, Video 129)
  - IVF (U-Matic 20 min.), 1987 (Box 6, Video 144)
  - IVF, Bagpipes 1 of 2(U-Matic 20 min.), 1987 (Box 5, Video 130)
  - IVF Chinese Painting (cont'd), needs audio dub (U-Matic 20 min.), 1987 (Box 5, Video 136)
  - IVF, Fiddle Puppets, a bit of Synthesis (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 26, 1987 (Box 5, Video 131)
  - IVF, Greek Carpets/Sewing, Chinese Paintings (U-Matic 20 min.), Aug 1, 1987 (Box 5, Video 133)
  - IVF, Green Grass Cloggers with Wildcats, FILE, MINAS, Main Stage, Sun. Nite Dance Party, 1987 (Box 7, Video 158)
  - IVF, 1. Gypsy Ballerinka (Mine Art) 2. Bulgarian Macedonian Albanian Group, 1 of 2 (U-Matic 60 min.), Jul 31, 1987 (Box 7, Video 153)
  - IVF: Khmer Trad Arts Ensemble (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 27, 1987 (Box 6, Video 141)
  - IVF, Odadaa, Fiddle Puppets Hambone Demo (U-Matic 20 min.), 1987 (Box 6, Video 140)
  - IVF Reception (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 28, 1987 (Box 6, Video 143)
  - IVF, Turkish Group, Hi Camera Angle #1, BF (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 27, 1987 (Box 5, Video 132)
  - IVF, Turkish Solo Folk Dance 2 of 3, Ground Level (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 27, 1987 (Box 5, Video 135)
  - IVF, Turkish (cont'd) 3 of 3 (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 27, 1987 (Box 6, Video 139)
  - IVF Turkish Group, also Khmer Classical Arts Assoc. (U-Matic 20 min.), 1987 (Box 6, Video 145)
  - IVF, Quatro Guitar Maker, Aguedo Beltram, Bagpipes (cont'd) (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 31, 1987 (Box 6, Video 146)
  - IVF Synthesis (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 26, 1987 (Box 5, Video 126)
  - International Village Fair (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 25, 1987 (Box 5, Video 137)
  - International Village Fair, Corncakes (cont'd), Lavaughn, (U-Matic 20 min.), undated (Box 5, Video 127)
  - International Village Faire, Khmer (Cambodian) Arts, (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 27, 1987 (Box 5, Video 128)
  - International Village Fair, "Latin American Traditions," Sukay, Tape 3 (U-Matic 60 min.), July 26, 1987 (Box 7, Video 156)
  - International Village Fair "Latin American Traditions," Vera Cruz Trio, Los Paraguayos, Tape 2 (U-Matic 60 min.), Jul 26, 1987 (Box 7, Video 154)
  - International Village Fair "Peking Opera," Tape 2, (U-Matic 60 min.), Jul 28, 1987 (Box 7, Video 155)
  - International Village Fair, Tape 1, Arts and Crafts (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 25, 1987 (Box 6, Video 142)
  - International Village Fair Vietnamese (cont'd) Turkish Folk Dance 1 of 2 (U-Matic 20 min.), Jul 27, 1987 (Box 5, Video 125)
  - Ireland Tour-Michael Dunlavey, Jul, 1995 (Box 4, Video 94)
  - Irish Ceili in the Glen-WNVC 56, undated (Box 1, Video 34)
  - Irish Ceili in the Glen, WNVC 56, undated (Box 4, Video 89)
  - Irish Concert, Gaston Hall, Georgetown University (unedited), undated (Box 2, Video 50)
  - Irish Concert-Mick Moloney with Eugene O'Donnell, John Jennings, Cedar Ridge High School, Old Bridge, NJ. Sponsor: Middlesex County Cultural and Heritage Commission., Dec 3, 1993 (Box 3, Video 75)
  - Irish Fest, undated (Box 3, Video 82)
  - Irish Folk Festival-Glen Echo, Tapes 1 and 2 of 8, 5/27/90, May 27, 1990 (Box 1, Video 42)
  - Irish Folk Festival Tapes 3 and 4 of 8, May 27, 1990 (Box 4, Video 104)
  - Irish Folk Festival, Tapes 5 and 6 of 8, May 27, 1990 (Box 4, Video 90)
  - Irish Folk Festival-Glen Echo, Tape 7 and 8 of 8, 5/27/90, May 27, 1990 (Box 2, Video 41)
  - Irish Folklore #2, S.W. to S.E. Coast, 1997 (Box 4, Video 99)
  - Irish Program '92, Rough Cut #2, Nov 23, 1992 (Box 4, Video 102)
  - Irish Traveller: Denu Party, undated (Box 4, Video 107)
  - "Irish Week," 1989, Head (Box 1, Video 36)
  - "Irish Week," 1989, Tail (Box 1, Video 36A)
  - Journey to Ireland, Part I and II, Nov 7, 1999 (Box 4, Video 91)
  - Kerry Dance (Box Shared Tamiment 137, Reel 8)
  - KET: The Kentucky Network, Mick Moloney, Robbie O'Connell, and Jimmy Keane with guest artists Eileen Ivers, fiddle, Donny Golden, step dancer, undated (Box 1, Video 21)
  - Kulintang Arts, Inc., Booking Tape 1989, RT 20:00 (Box 1, Video 4)
  - Laguna Dancers (Part I) (U-Matic 60 min.), undated (Box 6, Video 149)
  - Lonesome Pine Special, Kentucky Center, Feb 14, 1986 (Box 3, Video 82)
  - Mick Moloney (Beta U-Matic 20 min.), May 16, 1984 (Box 4, Video 111)
  - Mick Moloney, Album #1(Beta), undated (Box 2, Video 57)
  - Mick Moloney, Convocation-J. Crowden, Tape 1 of 2, RT 85:00, Phelps Stokes 102095, RDL #413014, undated (Box 1, Video 1)
  - Mick Moloney, Convocation J.Crowden, Tape 2 of 2, Phelps Stokes, Oct 20, 1995 (Box 3, Video 81)
  - Mick Moloney, Seamus Egan, Seamus Connolly at Midnight Express, Anchorage, Alaska, 1992 (Box 2, Video 44)
  - Mick Moloney and Friends-Folklife Center, undated (Box 2, Video 54)
  - Mick Moloney and Eugene O'Donnell GU, undated (Box 2, Video 47)
  - Mick Moloney and Eugene O'Donnell, FSLW Concert, Abby Sternberg, Sep 12, 1992 (Box 3, Video 83)
  - Mick Moloney Safety Master (Beta), Oct 22 (Box 2, Video 58)
  - Mick Moloney Safety Master (Beta), May 30, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Mick Moloney's Irish Folklore Tours, undated (Box 3, Video 66)
  - Mick Moloney's Irish Folklore Tour, Evening Concerts, undated (Box 2, Video 49)
  - Mick Sr. and Maura Moloney and Nannette Naoimny, (249) Vienny and Rentelle Goldstein; Anniversary Party, undated (Box 3, Video 61)
  - Milwaukee Irish Fest 2000, Cherish the Ladies and the Scattering, Aug 20, 2000 (Box 2, Video 26)
  - Milwaukee Irish Fest, Sliabh Notes (14 min), Mick Moloney and Friends, Aug 18, 2000 (Box 2, Video 28)
  - Milwaukee Fest, Tape 2, 1983 (Box 3, Video 63)
  - Miscellaneous/Middle East/Pipemaker #1 (U-Matic 20 min.), undated (Box 5, Video 124)
  - Musicmakers, Seamus Connolly and Friends, 1991 (Box 4, Video 101)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, National Heritage Fellowship Award Winners Concert, Kentucky Center for the Arts and KET the Kentucky Network, undated (Box 3, Video 80)
  - NEA Folks Arts Program, National Heritage Fellowships, September 1989, Parts 2 and 3, Sep, 1989 (Box 1, Video 11)
  - New Irish in America: Living in the Shadows, undated (Box 2, Video 56)
  - No Irish Need Apply, RT 28:20, undated (Box 3, Video 71)
  - NTSC Green Fields of America, undated (Box 3, Video 64)
  - Joe and Siobhan O'Donovan, Irish Dance Masters-Co.Cork, undated (Box 2, Video 31)
  - Old-Time Country Music, Cherish the Ladies, undated (Box 4, Video 96)
  - Daniel O'Meara, Final Research Project, Irish Music, Jerry O'Sullivan, Documentary-Edited, undated (Box 1, Video 8)
  - Daniel O'Meara, Final Research Project, Irish Music, Jerry O'Sullivan, Interview Footage, Not Edited, undated (Box 1, Video 7)
  - Music Live Rostrevor, undated (Box 4, Video 109)
  - "One Fond Embrace," Thomas Kinsella, the Irish Writer and a Duel Tradition, undated (Box 1, Video 22)
  - "One Fond Embrace," Thomas Kinsella, the Irish Writer and a Duel Tradition [a second copy], undated (Box 1, Video 23)
  - Our Lives Our Songs, Master, Harrisburg 5/7/1994, May 7, 1994 (Box 1, Video 20)
  - Out of Ireland, Produced by Paul Wagner and Ellen Casey Wagner, TRT-111 minutes, undated (Box 3, Video 61)
  - Out of Ireland: The Story of Irish Emigration to America, Narrated by Kelly McGillis, 1995 (Box 2, Video 25)
  - Part 1, undated (Box 1, Video 16)
  - Phila Ceili Group Festival, 1981 (Box 4, Video 97)
  - Phila Ceili Group Festival, September 11, 1982, Sep 11,1982 (Box 1, Video 32)
  - Philadelphia Ceili Group Festival, undated (Box 2, Video 45)
  - Phila Folk Fest Evening Concert, 1983 (Box 3, Video 60)
  - Pipe Maker Interview #2/Steel Drum Artist Interview (U-Matic 20 min.), undated (Box 5, Video 121)
  - Road to Dunmore and Jigs, Mick Moloney, "There were Roses" (Beta), undated (Box 4, Video 117)
  - Micho Russell, Interviewed by Mick Moloney, undated (Box 2, Video 52)
  - Micho at Washington Square Church, undated (Box 2, Video 53)
  - Safety for Songs Only, undated (Box 4, Video 98)
  - Saftey Master, Cherish the Ladies-producer Mick Moloney (Beta U-Matic 20 min.), Oct, 1985 (Box 4, Video 112)
  - SF Symphony Adventures in Music, Wind Ensemble, Potrero Hill Middle School, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Video 105)
  - Serbian Music Zydeco Film, undated (Box 4, Video 100)
  - SFISC Concert, 2/12/2000, Mick Moloney and Marie Reilly, Feb 12, 2000 (Box 1, Video 6)
  - Smithsonian Ireland Music Tour, 2001 (Box 3, Video 72)
  - Smithsonian Study Tours-The Music and Dance of Ireland (Sept. 7-17, 2000). Music Session at Roisin Dubh Pub (Sept. 14, 2000). Mick Moloney, Peter Horan, Greg Daly., Sep, 2000 (Box 3, Video 69)
  - Smithsonian Study Tours, The Music and Dance of Ireland, 9/7-14/2000, Music Session at the roisin Dubh Pub, 9/14/2000, Sep 9-14, 2000 (Box 1, Video 51)
  - Stateside, undated (Box 1, Video 24)
  - St. Patrick's Day, undated (Box 1, Video 19)
  - "Streets of the Capitol," 1994, Rhythm in Shoes (Box 1, Video 13)
  - Summer Solstice Folk Music and Dance Festival, Mar 28, 1994 (Box 2, Video 38)
  - Tape to Mick Moloney from Jon Williams, undated (Box 3, Video 70)
  - Finta Tawie et al (?), undated (Box 3, Video 87)
  - There were Roses, Mick/Rob/James Safty (Beta), Nov 14, 1985 (Box 4, Video 119)
  - Title No: AF 25977, Traditional American Dance-Promo, Running Time (4 min, 41 secs), Color, Language: Music and Effects, undated (Box 2, Video 59)
  - [Unmarked], undated (Box 1, Video 17)
  - [Unmarked], undated (Box 1, Video 18)
  - [Unmarked] (Box 4, Video 92)
  - Virgin Islands Music: Sounds of Cultural Rhythms, undated (Box 2, Video 39)